{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following was the first amino acid to be produced commercially?", "opta": "L-glutamic acid", "optb": "L-lysine", "optc": "L-cystine", "optd": "L-methionine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Candida species require fermentation equipment lined with plastic because they are extremely sensitive to", "opta": "traces of cobalt", "optb": "traces of nickel", "optc": "traces of iron", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cycloserine may be isolated from the cultures of", "opta": "S. orchidaceus", "optb": "S. lavendulae", "optc": "S. garyphalus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first penicillin isolated by Alexander Fleming, penicillin F is also called", "opta": "2-Pentenyl Penicillin", "optb": "n-heptyl penicillin", "optc": "phenoxymethyl penicillin", "optd": "benzyl penicillin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is mandatory that cultures and fermentation residues be sterilized before discard in case of Eremothecium ashbyii and Ashbya gossypii because they are", "opta": "plant pathogens", "optb": "human pathogens", "optc": "plant mutants", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following when used in proper concentration stimulates the Ascomycetes fermentation of vitamin B12 and can be used to counteract toxicity of iron in Candida species?", "opta": "Co", "optb": "Ni", "optc": "Zn", "optd": "Ca", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pectinase, an enzyme used for increasing yield and for clarifying juice is obtained by", "opta": "A. oryzae", "optb": "A. niger", "optc": "A.flavus", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 95% ethanol is equivalent to", "opta": "190 proof", "optb": "110 proof", "optc": "170 proof", "optd": "120 proof", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which species from the followings is resistant to methyl tryptophan?", "opta": "Candida utilis", "optb": "E. coli", "optc": "B. subtilis", "optd": "Hansenula anomala", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following substance is employed to neutralize the lactic acid as it is produced (because lactic acid bacteria do not tolerate high concentrations of acid?", "opta": "CaCO3", "optb": "(NH4)2 HPO4", "optc": "MgSO4", "optd": "Na2SO4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alcohol production from starch and raw sugar utilizes selected strains of", "opta": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "optb": "Candida pseudotropicalis", "optc": "Candida utilis", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungal amylases using stationary culture with wheat bran utilizes", "opta": "A. oryzae", "optb": "A. niger", "optc": "A. flavus", "optd": "S. cerevisiae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why high concentration of sugars are not employed in the fermentation medium?", "opta": "Calcium lactate is not produced", "optb": "Calcium lactate crystallizes from the medium and slows down the process of fermentation", "optc": "High sugar concentration itself crystallizes", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism produces enzyme taka diastase?", "opta": "A. oryzae", "optb": "B. subtilis", "optc": "A. niger", "optd": "S. cerevisiae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an industrial product made by the fungus Aspergillus niger?", "opta": "Galactosidase", "optb": "Citric acid", "optc": "Gluconic acid", "optd": "Lysine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The biotin level in obtaining L-gluatmic acid by fermentation using Micrococcus glutamicus is critical because", "opta": "too low level prevents growths, hence L-glutamic acid production", "optb": "too high level prevents L-glutamic acid production", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most productive species among the different vitamin B12 producing Pseudomonads is", "opta": "P. denitrificans", "optb": "P. ovalis", "optc": "P. aureofaciens", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme which converts optically active isomers of lactic acid to the optically inactive racemic mixture is", "opta": "isomerase", "optb": "racemase", "optc": "dehydrogenase", "optd": "invertase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sugar concentration of molasses used in fermentation should be", "opta": "10-18%", "optb": "20-30%", "optc": "4-5%", "optd": "30-38%", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacitracin, an antibiotic similar to penicillin, is produced by", "opta": "Bacillus polymyxa", "optb": "Streptomyces erythreus", "optc": "Bacillus licheniformis", "optd": "Aspergillus fumigatus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following Ascomycetes are used for riboflavin production?", "opta": "Eremnothecium ashbyii", "optb": "Ashbya gossypii", "optc": "Candida guilliermondia", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "B. flavum strain can be used for the production of", "opta": "L-Threonine", "optb": "L-Proline", "optc": "L-Isoleucine and L-Histidine", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A major organism used in commercial bioleaching for copper recovery is", "opta": "Desulfovibrio desulfuricans", "optb": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optc": "Aspergillus niger", "optd": "Thiobacillus ferrooxidans", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During fermentation, pyruvic acid is converted into organic products such as", "opta": "glucose and fructose", "optb": "starch and cellulose", "optc": "ethyl alcohol and lactic acid", "optd": "citric acid and isocitric acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are true for the heterofermentative microorganism producing lactic acid?", "opta": "Only trace amounts of end products other than lactic acid", "optb": "Some lactic acid with carbon dioxide, ethyl alcohol, acetic acid and trace amount of few other products", "optc": "They are used for commercial lactic acid production", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The submerged fermentation of vinegar utilizes special fermentor designs known as", "opta": "acetator", "optb": "cavitator", "optc": "packed vinegar generator", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major organism used in the microbial production of citric acid is", "opta": "Penicillin notatum", "optb": "Rhizopus nigrificins", "optc": "Aspergillus niger", "optd": "Lactobacillis delbrueckii", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism is utilized for the production of D-L-alanine?", "opta": "Microbacterium ammoniaphilum", "optb": "Brevibacterium flavum", "optc": "Arthrobacter paraffineus", "optd": "C. glutamicum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The aerated submerged bacterial fermentation to produce vitamin B12 employs strains of", "opta": "Propionibacterium", "optb": "Pseudomonas", "optc": "Acetobacter", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a heterofermentative micro-organism?", "opta": "Leuconostoc mesenteroides", "optb": "Lactobacillus delbrueckii", "optc": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optd": "Lactobacillus pentose", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Riboflavin is a by-product of __________ fermentation carried out by Clostridium spp.", "opta": "citric acid", "optb": "acetone butanol", "optc": "streptomycin", "optd": "ethanol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rickes et al. recovered active crystalline vitamin B12 from the culture of", "opta": "Streptomyces griseus", "optb": "Bacillus megaterium", "optc": "Streptomyces olivaceus", "optd": "Streptomyces lactis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rapid process of microbial oxidation developed to produce acetic acid from ethanol at Schutzenbach, Germany is also known as", "opta": "packed generator", "optb": "trickle method", "optc": "Orleans process", "optd": "both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following micro organism utilizes lactose as a carbon source in production of lactic acid from whey media?", "opta": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optb": "Lactobacillus delbrueckii", "optc": "Lactobacillus pentosus", "optd": "Leuconostoc mesenteroides", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism which utilizes the pentose of sulphite waste liquor for lactic acid production is", "opta": "Streptococcus lactis", "optb": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "optc": "Lactobacillus casei", "optd": "Lactobacillus pentosus", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chlorotetracycline a broad spectrum antibiotic is produced by", "opta": "Streptomyces aureofaciens", "optb": "Streptomyces rimosus", "optc": "Streptomyces venezuelae", "optd": "Streptomyces erythreus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The production of acetic acid from ethanol is an", "opta": "anaerobic process", "optb": "aerobic process", "optc": "a combination of both", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following agents involve biosensors linking with electronic circuit?", "opta": "Microorganisms", "optb": "Microbially derived enzymes", "optc": "Either microorganisms or microbially derived enzymes", "optd": "Neither microorganisms nor microbially derived enzymes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03b2-carotene is also known as", "opta": "vitamin A", "optb": "provitamin A", "optc": "vitamin C", "optd": "vitamin D", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vinegar is a fermentation derived food product containing not less than", "opta": "4% acetic acid", "optb": "15% acetic acid", "optc": "25% acetic acid", "optd": "6% acetic acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum concentration of ethanol that is achieved by successive distillation of fermentation broth in continuous stills is", "opta": "60%", "optb": "95%", "optc": "70%", "optd": "99%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The strain C. glutamicum can be used for the production of", "opta": "L-ornithine", "optb": "L-phenylalanine", "optc": "L-glutamine", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is known for greater stability of the riboflavin producing capacity?", "opta": "Eremothecium ashbyii", "optb": "Ashbya gossypii", "optc": "Candida flareri", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Species of the genus Streptomyces are known for", "opta": "the production of antibiotics", "optb": "the production of beer", "optc": "the production of cheese", "optd": "nitrification", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism used to produce L-glutamic acid is", "opta": "Micrococcus glutamicus", "optb": "Brevibacterium aminogenes", "optc": "Arthrobacter globiformis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The species of Acetobacter which produces cellulosic strands to hold the cells in lime layer is", "opta": "Acetobacter curvum", "optb": "Accetobacter orleanense", "optc": "Acetobacter xylinum", "optd": "Acetobacter schuetzenbachii", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonly used media for submerged bacterial fermentation at commercial scale is", "opta": "beet molasses", "optb": "liver extract", "optc": "germinated seed", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following microorganism produces only L(+) - lactic acid without further racemization ?", "opta": "Leuconostoc mesenteroides", "optb": "Lactobacillus delbrueckii", "optc": "Rhizopus oryzae", "optd": "Lactobacillus bulgaricus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The recovery of vitamin from fermentation broth is carried out prior to", "opta": "acidification", "optb": "alcohol treatment", "optc": "autolysis", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Naringinase, an enzyme commonly used for removal of bitter taste from citrus juice is obtained from", "opta": "A. niger", "optb": "A.flavus", "optc": "A. oryzae", "optd": "S. cerevisiae", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Protease, which is used for flavouring of sake and haze removal in sake is produced by", "opta": "A. oryzae", "optb": "A. flavus", "optc": "B. cereus", "optd": "A. niger", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism B. brevis can be used commercially for the production of", "opta": "gramicidin A", "optb": "tyrothricin(bacitracin tyrocidin complex)", "optc": "tyrocidin", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The early assay employed for measuring penicillin activity were based upon the quantity required to prevent growth of S. aureus over", "opta": "20 mm diameter zone using the cylinder plate method of assay", "optb": "24 mm diameter zone using the cylinder plate method of assay", "optc": "200 mm diameter zone using the cylinder plate method of assay", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Penicillin G is also known as", "opta": "hydroxy benzyl penicillin", "optb": "phenoxy methyl penicillin", "optc": "benzyl penicillin", "optd": "2-pentenyl penicillin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A major organic acid produced by a microbial process used in foods is", "opta": "sulfuric acid", "optb": "citric acid", "optc": "oxalic acid", "optd": "uric acid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}